<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ava Francesca Battocchio</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ava Francesca Battocchio</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.139.4</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Location</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/location/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/location/</guid>
      <description>Ava Francesca Battocchio&amp;#39;s mailing and office addresses at Michigan State University.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Office Hours</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/officehours/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 May 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/officehours/</guid>
      <description>Schedule and location for Ava Francesca&amp;#39;s office hours.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Identity Driven Information Ecosystems</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/8/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Mar 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/8/</guid>
      <description>This article presents the Identity Driven Information Ecosystem (IDIE) approach, showing how identity shapes information exposure and processing, illustrated by COVID-19.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Who Will Tell the Stories of Health Inequities? Platform Challenges (and Opportunities) in Local Civic Information Infrastructure</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/7/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/7/</guid>
      <description>This study explores how the decline in local news affects information accessibility about COVID-19 health disparities. Analyzing interviews and Facebook posts from six Great Lakes communities, it finds limited health disparity discussion, mostly generated by local news outlets, highlighting the role of digital platforms in local civic information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“Do Good and Be ‘Liked’”: CSR Messages on Social Media during COVID-19 Pandemic and Consumer Responses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/6/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/6/</guid>
      <description>This study examines CSR messages on social media during COVID-19 and their impact on consumer engagement, brand attitudes, and trust.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NAME</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/p1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/p1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;div class=&#34;thinline&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;thinline&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;heading&#34;&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 11: Gen Z&#39;s civic engagement: news use, politics, and cultural engagement</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/4/</guid>
      <description>This chapter explores Gen Z&amp;#39;s civic identities and digital media&amp;#39;s role in shaping their engagement with public life amid significant challenges.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapter 12: Gen Z&#39;s civic engagement: civic skills, political expression, and identity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/5/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/5/</guid>
      <description>Examining Gen Z&amp;#39;s evolving civic identity, socio-economic status, and digital media&amp;#39;s impact on political engagement and socialization.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>LaTeX Template for PhD Student</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/d1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/d1/</guid>
      <description>This template produces an academic presentation with LaTeX and Beamer. The presentation follows typographical best practices and has a minimalist design.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>“I Use Social Media as an Escape from All That” Personal Platform Architecture and the Labor of Avoiding News</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/3/</guid>
      <description>This study explores how U.S. young adults design their media worlds across platforms, impacting news use, based on 50 guided interviews on social media.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research Methods for Account Planning</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/c1/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/c1/</guid>
      <description>description</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Brand Authenticity on Social Media: The Impact of Instagram Ad Model Genuineness and Trustworthiness on Perceived Brand Authenticity and Consumer Responses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/2/</guid>
      <description>Smiling faces and snapshot aesthetics on Instagram boost perceived source genuineness, enhancing brand authenticity, trust, and consumer intentions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Effects of Transparent Brand Communication on Perceived Brand Authenticity and Consumer Responses</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/1/</guid>
      <description>Brands&amp;#39; transparent communication about production and costs boosts consumers&amp;#39; perceptions of transparency, authenticity, trust, and intentions</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;about-me&#34;&gt;About Me&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;div style=&#34;overflow: hidden;&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div style=&#34;float: right; margin: 0 0 10px 10px; width: 30%;&#34;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/Battocchio-fieldwork.png&#34; style=&#34;width: 100%;&#34; /&gt;
        &lt;div style=&#34;text-align: center; font-size: 14px; font-style: italic;&#34;&gt;
            Lake Superior during fieldwork
        &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;div&gt;
        Hiya! My name is Ava Francesca! I&#39;m an &lt;a href=&#34;https://comartsci.msu.edu/our-people/ava-francesca-battocchio&#34;&gt;Information and Media&lt;/a&gt; PhD Candidate and University Enrichment Fellow in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://comartsci.msu.edu/departments/advertising-public-relations&#34;&gt;Department of Advertising and Public Relations&lt;/a&gt; at Michigan State University, where I am advised by Dr. Kjerstin Thorson. In Fall 2025, I will be joining Northwestern University&#39;s Medill School of Journalism, Media, Integrated Marketing Communications as an Assistant Professor of Journalism. &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;br&gt;
        &lt;h3&gt;Research Interests&lt;/h3&gt;
        My work focuses on how residents in rural, remote, and post-industrial North American communities learn about public issues amidst changing technology, digital access disparities, and declining local news. This includes how critical information is produced and circulated by non-news actors, like non-profits, local governments, and municipal services, alongside news media.&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        My research highlights the role of place identity in critical information access and dissemination, particularly in the northern Great Lakes region. My dissertation examines this within the regional context of Michigan&#39;s remote Upper Peninsula(UP) and critical health and safety information.  &lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
        I love mixing ethnographic and computational methods to tackle these questions. I have been conducting fieldwork in the UP since Summer 2022. I pair these insights with textual analysis of digital trace data, such as Facebook posts, as well as spatial visualization (using R and ggplot) of public datasets and trace data.
    &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&#34;thinline&#34;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;h3 id=&#34;professional-affiliations-and-service&#34;&gt;Professional Affiliations and Service&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 2021, I have been the graduate student lab manager in the &lt;a href=&#34;https://comartsci.msu.edu/civic-infrastructure-lab&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Civic Infrastructure Lab&lt;/a&gt;
. I am also an affiliate with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://ruralcomputing.msu.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rural Computing Research Consortium&lt;/a&gt;
, as well as a Research Fellow with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://quello.msu.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quello Center&lt;/a&gt;
.
&lt;br&gt;&lt;br&gt;
Outside of Michigan State, I am an affiliate with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://citap.unc.edu/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Center for Information, Technology, and Public Life&lt;/a&gt;
. I also serve as a graduate student liaison to both the AEJMC History Division and AEJMC Communication Theory and Methods Division.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h3 id=&#34;news-and-updates&#34;&gt;News and Updates&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;December 2024:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I am officially off the academic job market! I&amp;rsquo;m over the moon to announce that I will be starting as a tenure-track Assistant Professor at Northwestern University in the Fall. I&amp;rsquo;m so excited to be joining the community at Medill and to be heading back to Chicago!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;July 2024:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently back from ICA (and feeding kangaroos) in Australia. My co-authors and I were awarded a Top Student-Led Paper by the Political Communication Division for our work on internet access and political participation across rural and urban communities in Michigan. It was amazing to present this work, as well integrate insights from my ongoing fieldwork to provide context for our survey findings. This presentation also gave me the opportunity to use the data-driven maps I&amp;rsquo;ve been building using ggplot, as I work through elements of my dissertation. It&amp;rsquo;s these moments that make me particularly excited about doing mixed-methods work in that drawing connections and triangulating data from different angles paints a rich picture of not only what is happening but reasons as to why it might be happening.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
